So, when we left off,
在上一步
I loaded in the VGG model with pre-trained weights,
我加载了具有预训练权重的 VGG 模型
and now I want to do two things.
现在我要执行两个任务
First, I want to freeze the weights in the features layers.
首先 我要冻结 features 层级中的权重
So, all the pre-trained convolutional weights will not change during training.
因此在训练期间 所有预训练的卷积权重将不变
Then this part of the VGG network will act as
VGG 网络的这部分将充当固定特征提取器
a fixed feature extractor that will operate on any input image in the same way.
并以相同的方式应用到所有输入图像上
Next, I want to replace
接下来 我将最后的线性层级
the last linear layer with a layer that outputs five-class scores,
替换为一个输出 5 个类别分数的层级
and I'll train the three fully-connected layers.
并训练这 3 个全连接层
So, let's scroll down and addressed the first task,
下拉 我们先解决第一个任务
freezing some pre-trained weights.
即冻结一些预训练的权重
To freeze the convolutional weights,
要冻结卷积权重
I'm going to iterate through every parameter in the list of VGG features parameters.
我将遍历 VGG features 参数列表中的每个参数
Recall that features is just the name of the group that
features 是指
encompasses all of these convolutional and pooling layers.
包含所有卷积层和池化层的一组层级的名称
And I'm going to say for every weight,
对于每个权重
the required grad property is false.
require_grad 属性为 false
PyTorch during training automatically keeps track of
在训练期间 PyTorch 会自动跟踪
the gradient of the training loss with respect to the model weights.
训练损失相对于模型权重的梯度
But, if this is set to false,
但是如果将这个属性设为 false
these weights will be left alone and not considered in those gradient calculations.
这些权重将被忽略并且在计算梯度时不会考虑它们
In other words, by setting this parameter property to false,
换句话说 通过将这个参数属性设为 false
we're freezing these weights and they'll stay at their pre-trained values.
我们冻结了这些权重 它们将保留预训练的值
Next, I want you to change the last layer of this model,
接下来 由你来更改模型的最后一个层级
and I think you know enough to try this task on your own.
你学习过的知识应该足以完成这个任务
All you need to do is grab this final fully-connected layer by name and number,
你只需按照名称和编号引用这个最后全连接层
and set it equal to a new linear layer
并将它设为新的线性层级
with the correct number of inputs and five outputs.
新线性层级具有正确的输入数量和 5 个输出
To define just one layer,
要定义一个层级
you'll use nn.linear, much like you would in the init function of a net class.
你要使用 nn.linear，就像在 net 类的 init 函数中定义层级一样
So, I'll leave this as a challenge for you to complete.
这部分将由你来完成
I'll also add one more challenge.
我还布置了一道练习
I'm going to leave this training loop empty.
我将这个训练循环留空了
You've seen a number of examples of the training loop,
我们已演示过好几个训练循环示例
and by using a reference or from memory,
请你参考前面的课程内容
I want you to code up
或凭记忆编写一个
an epic and batch loop that iterates just through the training data.
遍历训练数据的周期和批次循环
I also want you to record the training loss as you go and print it out.
此外 请记录训练损失并输出损失
Next, I'll show you how to add a final layer and train the complete model.
接下来我将演示如何添加最后的层级并训练整个模型